≪(宇佐)先輩
Senpai!
今 帰りですか？
Are you heading home?
(律)うん
偶然っすね
Yeah.
What a coincidence!
俺も今日 日直で遅くなっちゃって
A lie
I left late because I was on day duty for my class today.
I see...
Real lie
自転車 パンクしてるの？
Did you blow out a tire on your bike?
<遠回しに 先に行ってくれと
言われてないか？>
Is that a roundabout way of telling me to go on ahead?
<だが 空気は読まない>
But I refuse to take the hint!
河合荘まで そう遠くないし
It's not that far from the Kawai Complex,
歩くのもいいかな～ と
so I thought I'd walk.
橋からの景色も
きれいだし
And the view from the bridge is nice.
同じ住人なんだし
We live in the same building, so you don't have to be so cold.
そんな邪険に
しないでくださいよ
Just a thought...
な～んて
<あッ あの先輩が本を閉じた！>
She actually shut her book!
<それで こんなに感動する俺も
どうなんだって感じだけど>
And I'm not sure what to think of myself for being so happy about that...
《(彩花)律ちゃんって
いつも一人で》
Rit-chan acts like she doesn't mind being alone,
《本当は
すごく寂しいんだと思うの》
but I think she's really lonely.
So please be there for her.
《だから 力になってあげて》
《宇佐君には
あんなに打ち解けてるし➡》
She's opened up to you so much.
I know you can do it.
《宇佐君なら 絶対いけるよ➡》
...can do it... can do it...
《いけるよ いけるよ…》
Is Sayaka-san right?
Can I do this?
<いけちゃうのかな？>
Maybe I need to be more forceful!
<ちょっと強引ぐらいが
いいのかも>
Episode Four
For the Time Being
≪(シロ)住子さん➡
Sumiko-san.
どうしたの？ それ
What are those?
These were a present from a friend.
(住子)お友達からもらったの
みんなで飲まない？
Would everyone like some?
(シロ)飲む！
飲む！
Yes!
Oh, the high school students get juice instead.
ああ 高校生組はジュースね
ですよね
Of course.
(麻弓)ああ せっかくだけど
私は やめとく
Oh, I appreciate the offer, but I have to pass. Sorry.
(一同)ええ～!?
そこまで驚くことねえだろ
Is it really that big of a shock?
新しくダメな彼氏でも
できたんですか？
Are you going out with a new jerk?
Why are you assuming that it would be a jerk?
なんで ダメ前提なんだよ
暴飲暴食 続いてたから
I've been drinking and eating too much,
so I'm trying to control myself.
ちょっと自粛してんの
肌にも よくないし
It's bad for my skin.
Come to think of it, you haven't been eating much lately.
そういえば最近
ご飯の量も減らしてたわね
前は 日本昔ばなしみたいに
食べてたのに
You used to fill up your bowl like those kids in folk tales.
What?
But your tummy's so soft and squishy right now!
せっかく もみ心地いいのに
下腹の
そんな心地は
私の腹にはねえ！
My tummy isn't supposed to be squishy!
じゃあ もむとこ
胸しかないじゃない
That only leaves your boobs for me to squeeze.
Why do you have to squeeze anything on me?!
なんで もむのが
義務みたいになってんだよ！
Is it the ex again?
まさか また元彼？
No, it's a friend.
ちげえよ 友達
Hello?
うん 大丈夫
Yeah, I can talk.
It's about next week, right?
来週のことだよね？
Huh?
そっか…
I see...
何て言っていいか
I don't know what to say.
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
うん 今日は ゆっくり休んで
All right.
You should get some rest, then.
Yeah, talk to you later.
うん じゃあ また
おいしいねえ
This is good.
どうしたの？ 麻弓ちゃん
What's wrong, Mayumi-chan?
Thanks
Tremble
My friend who was going out with this elite guy said,
エリートの彼氏持ちの友達が
Thanks
Tremble
｢彼の友達と合コン
セッティングしてあげる｣ って
"I'll set up a mixer with my boyfriend's friends!"
Tremble
to me in a vaguely stuck-up tone, then she said,
微妙に上から目線で
企画してくれて
｢ちょっと体絞ったほうがいいよ
ブブッ｣
"You should lose some weight. Hehe!"
lel
Like she was giving me advice...
Tremble
なんて アドバイスもくれて
She sounds like a wonderful friend.
素敵な友達ですね
But she just told me she broke up with her boyfriend, so the mixer's off.
でも 彼と別れたから…
…って 今
Should I be disappointed? Should I feel bad for her?
惜しめばいいのか いたわれば
いいのか 喜べばいいのか
Should I be happy?
間違えたら最悪だ～
If I make the wrong call, I'll be an awful person.
The fact that you're torn between those makes you awful already.
悩む時点で最悪なので
安心してください つーか
And I can only see "disappointed" and "happy" on your face.
…しかないよ その顔ッ
I don't wanna be a woman who's happy to see her friends suffer!
嫌だ 友達の不幸を喜ぶ女なんて
他人ならいいけど
It's fine if it's a stranger, though!
よくないすよ
でも 麻弓ちゃん
No, it's not.
Mayumi-chan, you never liked that friend to begin with, right?
そのお友達
元から かなり嫌いでしょ？
Uh-huh.
うん
じゃあ 割と他人じゃないかしら
Then she's essentially a stranger, right?
I just realized that there was no reason for me to hit Shiro.
…て よく考えたらシロ殴る必要性
まったくなかったな
≪(彩花)いいんじゃない？
シロさんだし
One more...
What's the problem? It's just Shiro-san.
True.
Well, you know...
まあ 何つーか
A girl can only have so many friends.
女の友情なんて 人数制限あんだよ
ほんとに仲いいのは ごく小数で
You really can only get close to a few.
ヒクッ あとは惰性だったり
With the others, you have to deal with habits
ヒクッ 妙なルールあったりして
めんどくせえよな
and all these weird rules.
It's such a pain.
分かる～
なあ？ 律ちゃん
I know what you mean!
Right, Rit-chan?
ええッ そんな偏った意見の同意
求められても
You want me to agree with a biased opinion like that?
私 同意してるのに
I'm agreeing with you!
喜々として女の敵に回って
ルールぶち壊せるやつに
I don't need a woman who gets her jollies out of
making enemies and breaking rules to agree with me.
同意されたくねえ
I'm not the only one who ignores rules.
ルール無視っつったら
Rit-chan never makes any friends.
律ちゃんだって 友達つくらないし
ちょっと 彩花さん
Wait! Sayaka-san!
I didn't choose to be alone...
好きで一人でいるわけじゃ…
That's right! Being drunk doesn't mean you can say whatever you want!
そうですよ 何てこと言うんですか
酔っ払いとはいえ
高校に入って最初のクラス
When I first entered high school,
同じ中学の子 他にいなくて
there wasn't anyone from my middle school in my class.
元々 うちの中学から
あの高校入るの少ないし
There weren't many people from my middle school at all there.
少ないというか あと男子
And they were all boys.
自分から話しかける
きっかけがなくて
I never found the right chance to talk to anyone,
so before I knew it, I was alone.
気づいたら一人で
It was less stressful, so I just accepted it.
なんか楽だし
まあ いいかって
It sure sounds like you chose to be alone.
<それ
割と好きで一人でいますよね>
Come on!
ほら 麻弓さんには
彩花がいるじゃないですか
You still have me!
I never asked for a friend who's after my body!
体目当てのやつを
友達にした覚えはない！
さあ そろそろ
お開きにしましょうか
Well, we should wrap this up.
They're already drunk, anyway.
麻弓ちゃん達 酔っ払ってるし
I'll never be able to get along with you!
お前とは うまくやれないから
楽って
うん？
Less stressful...
絶対 無理してますよね
I can tell she's trying too hard.
宇佐君には そう見えるの？
Does it look that way to you?
Well, I think she must be lonely.
いや でも
寂しいんじゃないかと
Are you sure?
どうかな
Girls in high school have to keep up
女子高生仲間って はやりとか
敏感じゃなきゃダメそうで
with all kinds of trends if they want to fit in.
大変っぽいし
It must be difficult.
はやり？ そういえば…
Trends...
That reminds me...
でも これは関係ないか
But I guess it's not relevant...
何ですか？
教えてください
What is it? Please tell me.
前に➡
Remember how loose socks used to be all the rage a while back?
ﾙｰｽﾞｿｯｸｽが大はやりしたろ？
うん
Yeah.
次のはやりは ルーズを受け継いだ
Following the "loose" theme, I think the next trend should be loose panties.
ﾙｰｽﾞﾊﾟﾝﾃｨｰってのは
どうかなと思うんだ
Jeez, they're sliding down again.
<やだ もう
また下がってきた>
They'd always have to hold their panties up through their skirts.
いつも こう
スカート越しに押さえたりして
Definitely not relevant.
本当に関係ないな
おやすみやがれ
Go to sleep already.
Not stressful...
<楽なんて…>
<きっと 無理を>
I'm sure she's trying too hard.
She must be.
Though it certainly doesn't look that way.
<してる感じは
まったくしないけども>
すっげえ楽しそう
She's really enjoying herself.
But...
<でも あんなふうに笑ったり>
After she was laughing and blushing like that before,
<先輩は いつも本を読みながら>
Senpai still spends all her time reading
in the living room.
先輩
Senpai!
また偶然ですね
What a coincidence, again.
うわッ…
今日は歩きなんすよ
I'm walking to school today.
<空気読むな 空気読むな>
I won't take a hint. I won't take a hint!
あの 宇佐君
Um, Usa-kun...
もしかして 昨日の話で
気を使ってくれてる？
Are you doing this because of what I said yesterday?
えッ？
だったら気にしないで
If so, it's not necessary.
I meant it when I said it's less stressful.
楽なのは ほんとだから
If I've read the books without seeing the TV series,
本読んでて ドラマ見てなかったり
メール返事遅れたり
or I don't get replies to e-mails,
携帯小説に
のめり込めなかったり
or I don't get into cell phone novels,
どこか行きたい？ って聞かれて
新刊買いに行きたいって答えて
or people ask me where I want to go and I say I want to buy the new release,
it doesn't get awkward if I'm alone.
すごく微妙な
空気にならないし 一人だと
That's all based on books!
<わざわざ こんなこと言うなんて>
If she's telling me all this,
does it mean she's actually lonely?
<ほんとのほんとは
寂しいんじゃないかな>
Isn't there anything I can do for her?!
<何か力になれないだろうか？>
That must be what he's thinking behind that look.
<…って 思ってんだろうな
あの目>
あの…
何ですか？
Um.
What is it?!
宇佐君 疲れないの？
Don't you ever get tired?
何がです？
What do you mean?
You always go along with other people.
いろんな人に うまく
合わせてるでしょ
People like Shiro-san, Mayumi-san, and Sayaka-san.
あのシロさんとか 麻弓さんとか
彩花さんとか
Huh? Is she showing concern for me?
<心配してくれてる？>
疲れてるなんて そんな
普通にしてるだけだし
I don't get tired.
I'm just acting normal.
What? He doesn't get tired?
そうなんだ すごいね
Really... That's impressive.
W-Was that... a compliment?
<これは
褒められた… んだよな？>
いや
そんな大げさな
It's not that big a deal...
He's not going along with them.
He thinks like them to begin with.
And I thought he seemed like a normal person.
<まともそうに見えてたのに
変なんだ>
He's just a weirdo.
Am I really making a good impression?
<ほんとに好印象持たれてる？>
<だとしたら やっぱり>
In that case, it means I do need to be more forceful!
Yes!
(住子)あら
Oh.
おかえり
Welcome back.
ただいま
I'm back!
I'm back...
I'll keep refusing to take the hint!
<頑張るぞ 空気読まずに！>
先輩 先輩
Senpai!
学校 行ってきます…
I'm going to school.
えッ もう？
What, already?
じゃあ 俺も 行ってきま～す
I'll join you, then!
Bye!
He's starting to remind me of my pet hamster back home.
最近 あいつ見てると
実家のハムスター思い出す
<先輩 来ないな>
Senpai hasn't come this way yet.
Maybe I'll check the book store.
So she was at the book store.
<先輩 本屋にいたのか>
先輩…
(同級生Ａ)あれ 律じゃね？
Sen—
Hey, isn't that Ritsu?
(Ｂ)ああ ほんとだ
Oh, you're right.
Are they her friends?
<先輩の友達？>
シーッ 律！
Ritsu!
びっくりしすぎ
久しぶりだね
You don't have to be so scared.
Haven't seen you in forever.
H-Her friends are pretty intense.
びっくりした
ほんと久しぶり
That scared me.
It's been forever!
中学卒業以来じゃない？
Since middle school graduation, right?
You still zone out when you're reading, I see.
相変わらず 本読むとダメだね
飛んじゃうもんね 律さんは
Ritsu-san goes into her own little world.
≪(Ａ)律の学校
うちの卒業生少ないから➡
We never hear about you
since there aren't many people from our middle school at your high school.
全然 噂聞かないし➡
We were worried that you might be all alone.
ぼっちになってないか
心配してたんだよ
Yeah!
うん
律ってば 不思議系入ってるしさ
You can be an odd one, you know.
What? That's not true.
えッ そんなことないよ
Oh, really?
ほんとに？
ほんとだってば
Yes, really.
<なんだ 先輩>
I guess she is enjoying herself.
携番変わったから交換しよう
うん
I got a new phone, so let's exchange numbers.
Sure.
We should have a get-together for everyone from middle school.
今度 中学のみんなでさ
集まんない？
ああ いいね
Yeah. That sounds great.
That's great.
See you around.
じゃあ またね
うん また
Yeah, see ya.
<えッ 何？ この まずい人に
まずいところを見られたって顔>
Er, why does she look like she really didn't want me to see that?
Wait!
Why...
<逃げるんだ？>
did she run away?
あの…
Uh...
先輩
Senpai?
え～と
Er...
I shouldn't take the hint,
right?
<いいんだよな？>
さっき よかった… ですね
That was really nice, right?
久しぶりに 友達に会えて
You got to see your friends again.
やめてよ
Stop it.
勝手に決めつけて
Stop making assumptions and worrying about me!
勝手に心配して
Enough is enough!
いい加減にして！
な～んちゃって
Just kidding...
ごめん
Sorry.
おい
Hey.
If you don't get up, I'm gonna kick you.
そんなとこ転がってると
蹴っ飛ばすぞ
どうぞ
なんだ
Go ahead...
Corpse
What? Did you catch Shiro's masochist germs?
シロのＭが うつったか？
Oh, I bet Rit-chan got mad at you.
さては 律ちゃんに怒られたか
分かってたなら
止めてくださいよ！
If you knew she'd get mad, you should have stopped me!
だって おもしろか…
But it was fun to—
It looked like fun to watch.
おもしろそうだったし
なんで言い直した
Did you really need to correct yourself?!
Plus, I've had it rough since you made me want to go visit home.
こっちも お前のせいで実家
帰りたくなって大変だったんだぞ
ハム次郎に会いたくなって
You made me want to see Hamjiro.
因果関係が
まるで分からない！
I'm failing to see the connection!
I told you not to believe anything that Sayaka says.
だから 彩花の言うことなんか
真に受けんなって言ってたろうが
But... she said that Senpai was opening up to me...
だって
先輩が俺には打ち解けてる とか
そんな嬉しいこと言われたから
It made me so happy to hear that,
信じちゃうじゃないすか
I had to believe her!
《だから 力になってあげて
宇佐君なら絶対いけるよ》
So please be there for her.
I know you can do it.
ああ
そこは まんざら嘘じゃねえからな
That part probably wasn't a lie.
Though I wouldn't go as far as to say she's opening up to you.
打ち解けてたっつーと
大げさだけど
R-Really?
ほんとに？
じゃあ…
That means...
Everything was fine as it was,
現状維持でよかったのに
俺ってば
頑張ってゴリゴリ墓穴を～！
but I went overboard and ruined everything!
Yes, good work!
は～い ご苦労さまでした
だから あいつは最悪なんだよ
I told you, she's as evil as they come.
Does she have to be such a bad person?!
たち悪すぎでしょ あの人
Feed
Think of it as training for being eaten by a lady spider.
まッ ジョロウグモに食われる
訓練と思っとけ
Feed
No first year should have to train for that!
高１でやる訓練じゃない！
そして うまみが
まるでない…
And I get nothing out of it!
Screw your youth!
青春なんてクソ食らえ
You're just as bad as she is!
あんたも大概 たち悪いから
プギャーッ！
律ちゃん？
Rit-chan?
そんなとこで何やってんの？
What are you doing over there?
草むしり
I'm pulling weeds.
Are you feeling down?
落ち込んでんの？
別に
分かりやすいな
Not really.
You're so easy to read.
宇佐君と何かあった？
Did something happen with Usa-kun?
なんで？
Why do you ask?
だって 宇佐君も
昨日から へこんでたし
Because Usa-kun's been moping since yesterday.
It wasn't really... with Usa-kun...
宇佐君と っていうか…
It's not like that!
《そうじゃなくて
ただ普通に仲よくなれたら》
I just want to get to know her better!
Since, you know, we live in the same place and go to the same school!
《ほら 同じ住人で高校も一緒だし
話したら おもしろそうだし》
I think she'd probably be fun to talk to!
I'm a little worried since she's always alone.
《先輩 いつも一人で
ちょっと心配っていうか》
Was that last comment necessary?
《最後のそれ いる？》
《≪(シロ)宇佐君 前途多難だね》
Usa-kun's got a rough road ahead...
I knew it.
Shiro-san and Senpai?
<シロさんと 先輩？>
Do I really look that lonely?
私 そんなに
寂しそうに見えるのかな
People talk when they both know they have nothing to say.
話 合わないの
お互い分かってるのに合わせたり
かけてこないのに 携番交換したり
They exchange phone numbers, but never call.
そういうのより
If that's how it is, I'd rather be alone.
一人のがいいのに
嫌いじゃないけど
I don't dislike people,
but I sometimes wish they'd just stop talking.
早く話終わらないかな とか
思ってたし
But I just smile and go with the flow...
でも 笑って調子合わせて
なのに
Yet, while I don't mind being alone,
一人は嫌じゃないのに
I don't want people to think that I'm alone.
一人だって思われるのは嫌で
Enough is enough!
《いい加減にして！》
矛盾ばっかで
I keep contradicting myself,
and I took it all out on Usa-kun...
宇佐君に 八つ当たりしちゃうし
もう…
Are you saying you hate yourself?
自分が嫌いってやつ～？
I don't really
get it, but...
何ですか それ バカみたい
Where'd you get that stupid idea?
青春の定番の悩みだよね
It's a typical concern that young people have.
そんなので悩みませんよ
めんどくさい
I wouldn't waste time worrying about that. Too much effort.
Well, I don't particularly like myself, either.
まあ 好きになれる気もしないけど
うん うん
ちょっ… 違いますって
Wait! You've got it all wrong!
When you're young, you want to keep everything neat.
若いときって 潔癖なとこあるよね
俺も そうだったな
I was the same way.
<俺 ほんと…>
I was completely off the mark.
でも いつかさ
But one day,
you'll learn to accept who you are.
まあ こんな自分もありかって
思えるよ
俺みたいに➡
The way I did.
だから 安心して悩むといいよ
So feel free to worry away.
Senpai's opening up to Shiro-san.
Don't tell me that she's in...
<まさか先輩 シロさんのこと…>
You don't hate yourself? Seriously?
シロさん 自分のこと
嫌いじゃないんですか そんなんで
ですよね～
I expected that.
<よかった 気のせいだった>
Good. It was just my imagination.
What, that didn't sound like a nice story?
あれ いい話っぽくなかった？
全然
Not at all.
Just as sharp as Sumiko-san!
住子さん譲りのバッサリ感
ハアハアッ ああ～ッ
That was just wrong.
<とりあえず…>
For now,
I'll take the hint.
<話しかけるのは やめよう>
I won't try to talk to her.
Still wants to
stand next to her
I'm standing next to her, but she still feels far away.
ハア…
Came back
<４回目の青信号 動く気配ゼロ>
That's the fourth green light, and she still hasn't moved.
Is she going to make it home?
<この人 ちゃんと帰れるのか？>
There's a lot of traffic. Isn't that dangerous?
<車とか いろいろ危ないだろ>
Come to think of it, she does come home late a lot.
<そういや 遅くに帰ってくること
多いような…>
She looks as happy as a little kid.
Man...
<ああ もう！>
先輩 青
Senpai, the light is green.
宇佐君
Usa-kun.
Wait!
あッ 閉じなくていいっすよ
Don't shut your book.
おもしろいんでしょ？
It's interesting, right?
ああ だから
So, I'm not saying that we should walk home together,
一緒に帰るとかではなくて
but we're going in the same direction...
でも 道は同じなわけだし
And if I don't say anything, you'll stand there forever.
ほっとくと
ずっと立ってそうだから
話をしたりとか
気にしなくて 別にいいんで
You don't have to worry about holding a conversation.
えっと
交通安全のおばちゃん的な？
Think of me as one of those ladies who
旗で誘導するのと一緒っつーか
waves flags to motion traffic through.
旗はないですけど
I don't have a flag on me, though.
何それ 変なの
What was that? You're weird.
宇佐君って ほんと変
You're so weird, Usa-kun.
<とりあえず これでいいんだ>
For now, this is enough.
先輩も大概 変でしょ
You're pretty weird yourself, Senpai!
うわッ もう夢中
She's already back to her book!
Currently
guiding traffic
あッ 先輩 先輩
Senpai! Senpai!
A rainbow!
虹！
わあ…
おっと すいません
邪魔して
Oh... Sorry for interrupting you.
Thank... you...
今 何か言いました？
Did you say something?
よく聞こえなくて
I couldn't hear you.
別に
Not really.
Okay...
じゃあ…
You're welcome.
どういたしまして
You heard me fine.
A
We'll
all
stay
pitiful
tomorrow
shi
ta
mo
bo
ku
ra
wa
mi
n
na
ka
wa
i
so
u
A
Preview
Hey, Senpai!
先輩 ｵｽｽﾒの本あったら
貸してもらえませんか？
Do you have any good books I could borrow?
Wow, Usa.
すげえな 律ちゃんが触ったものは
何でもオカズにできる その童貞力
You have the virgin power to get off to anything Rit-chan has touched!
The imagination of a teenage boy is limitless!
(シロ)思春期の妄想は無限大だね
そういう使い方は想定してません
I shouldn't need to say this, but I wasn't planning to use them that way!
(彩花)重石にして お漬物作る？
You plan to use them as weights to pickle veggies?
I know! You're going to lift books to get into shape so you can run from cops!
(ｼﾛ)筋力ﾄﾚｰﾆﾝｸﾞに使い 引きこもり
がちな毎日の運動不足を…
Don't bring me to your level!
一緒にしないでください！
(彩花)何に使うの？
Then what are you gonna use them for?
What else?! I'm following Senpai's example and...
俺だって先輩みたいに…
ああ 武器として使うのか
Rit-chan's example? Oh, you're going to use them as weapons?
重い本が攻撃力高くて角が有効
先輩まで～
Heavier books hit harder, and the corners are effective...
Episode Five
I Knew It
You too, Senpai?!